Joseph Charles Muhler papers, 1919-1997 C356
Indiana University Archives
- Publications, 1938-1984; undated (Box 12)
  - Topical Treatment of the Teeth with Stannous Fluoride, Single Application Technique, 1958; undated (Box 16)
  - What Motivates Children to Practice Good Oral Hygiene, 1959 (Box 16)
  - WHO (World Health Organization), Fluorides and Dental Health, Chapter 2.3, Ingestion from Foods, 1964-1969; undated (Box 16)
  - Xerox College Publishing Introduction to Chemistry, 1972-1973 (Box 16)
- Subject files, 1941-1997; undated (Box 17)
  - Advanced Preventative Dentistry (lecture), 1959-1961; undated (Box 17)
  - Alumni Association, 1982-1987 (Box 17)
  - Alumni Association Camp, 1978 (Box 17)
  - Alumni Bulletin, Indiana University School of Dentistry, 1990-1993 (Box 17)
  - American Association of Cereal Chemists, 1990 (Box 17)
  - American Association of Dental Textbook Authors, 1965 (Box 17)
  - American Chemical Society, 1955-1957; 1965-1971; 1982 (Box 17)
  - American College of Dentists, 1957-1964; undated (Box 17)
  - American College of Dentists, Meeting and ADA (American Dental Association) Meeting, 1967; undated (Box 17)
  - American Dental Association (Box 17)
    - 1964 (Box 17)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 17)
  - American Dental Association, Funds from Industry for Dental Education, 1957 (Box 17)
  - ADA Presentation, Las Vegas, 1965 (Box 17)
  - ADA Presentation, Las Vegas, George Stookey, 1965 (Box 17)
  - American Institute of Chemists (Box 17)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 17)
    - 1983-1986, undated (Box 17)
  - American Public Health Association (Dr. Muhler's Membership), 1964; undated (Box 17)
  - American Society for Preventative Dentistry, 1967-1968; undated (Box 17)
  - American Society of Dentistry for Children, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Animal Care Committee, 1975-1985 (Box 17)
  - Annual Meeting of American Association of Dental Schools, (March 22, 1960); 1959-1960; undated (Box 17)
  - Annual Report, Indiana University School of Dentistry, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Annual Report to Dean McDonald, 1975 (Box 17)
  - Applications-MS and MDS, 1973; undated (Box 17)
  - Appointment Book, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Arizona Dental Meeting, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Armstrong, William, 1988-1989 (Box 17)
  - Association of Indiana University Chemists Newsletter, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Atlanta Meeting, 1970; undated (Box 17)
  - Bacteriology, undated (Box 17)
  - Senator Bayh, (April 1965); 1965; undated (Box 17)
  - Bibliography of Dentifrice Lecture, 1958-1969 (Box 17)
  - Billings, Montana Dental Education Program, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Biochemistry, 1944-1945; undated (Box 17)
  - Biochemistry 101, 1974-1975; undated (Box 17)
  - Brush-In, 1969 (Box 17)
  - California Dental Association, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Cancelled, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Chemistry, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Chemistry 221, undated (Box 17)
  - Clev-Dent Catalog, 1951 (Box 17)
  - Clinical Preventative Dentistry (D-714) Syllabus, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Colorado Society of Children, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Concerned Titled Professors, 1983 (Box 17)
  - Consumers Union Article by Mr. Leonard, 1968-1969; undated (Box 17)
  - Contacts, undated (Box 17)
  - Course Evaluations, undated (Box 17)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Dahl-Ideas for Papers, Clinics, etc., undated (Box 17)
  - Dahl, Lillian and Nancy Dudding Patient Reaction to Brushing Teeth, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Dr. Harry G. Day., 1957; undated (Box 17)
  - Dental Conventions (Box 17)
    - 1973-1981 (Box 17)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 17)
  - Dental I.Q. Test, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Detroit Speaking Engagement, 1957-1958 (Box 17)
  - Distinguished Alumni Service Award, 1974-1987; undated (Box 17)
  - Eastman Dental Dispensary Symposium, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Endowed Chair in Preventative Dentistry, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Exams, undated (Box 17)
  - An Experimental Program to Develop Methods and Techniques for Teaching Health Education in the Elementary and Secondary Schools, 1961; undated (Box 17)
  - Faculty Annual Summary Report, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Fall Conference-Alumni Association, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Federal Aid Notification, undated (Box 17)
  - Grant Applications (Box 17)
    - 1973-1978, undated (Box 17)
    - 1981-1983, undated (Box 17)
  - Harrison, Earl R., 1946-1947; undated (Box 17)
  - Hawaii State Dental Association, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Health Education Program Indiana State Board of Health, undated (Box 17)
  - Helmke Library, 1982-1985 (Box 17)
  - I'll Buy That, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Indiana Academy, 1982-1987 (Box 17)
  - Indiana Academy of Science, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Indiana Convention, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Indiana Dental Association, 1970; 1988; undated (Box 17)
  - Indiana Dental Association Journal, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Indiana Dental Health Task Force, undated (Box 17)
  - IU Football, 1983-1996; undated (Box 17)
  - Indiana Public Health Foundation, Inc., 1966-1969; undated (Box 17)
  - Indiana University, 1972-1974 (Box 17)
  - Indiana University Agreements File #2, 1972; undated (Box 17)
  - Indiana University Alumni, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Indiana University Alumni Association Family Camps, undated (Box 18)
  - Indiana University, Long Range Plan (Box 18)
    - 1974 (Box 18)
    - 1974-1984, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Indiana University Muhler Contracts, 1964-1969; 1972-1988; undated (Box 18)
  - Indiana University-Purdue University at Indianapolis (IUPUI), 1973-1979 (Box 18)
  - Indiana University Purdue University Foundation Fort Wayne, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Indiana University School of Dentistry Alumni Association, 1959-1966 (Box 18)
  - Indiana University School of Dentistry Class Photographs, 1961-1966 (Box 18)
  - IU Wrestling, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Institute for Advanced Research, Reports, undated (Box 18)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, Report (Box 18)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 18)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 18)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 18)
  - IADR (International Association for Dental Research) Meeting, 1976 (Box 18)
  - IADR Meetings and Correspondence, 1953-1958; undated (Box 18)
  - International Harvester World, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Introduction to Laboratory Work in Chemistry, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Journals-Binding, 1975-1986 (Box 18)
  - Journal, Ind. Dent. Assn., 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Journal of Oral Therapeutics and Pharmacology, Dr. Austin Kutscher, Editor, 1964-1965; undated (Box 18)
  - Key to Periodic Chart, 1941 (Box 18)
  - Korea-Hawaii, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Korea Photographs, Joe Butcher, 1985 (Box 18)
  - McCollum, E. V., 1979-1980; 1987 (Box 18)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 52 Pearls, Nutrition, and P.D., 1957-1962 (Box 18)
  - Mexico Dental Meeting, (1967); undated (Box 18)
  - Mexico Presentation, 1966-1967; undated (Box 18)
  - Minnesota Dental Association, March 1966 (Box 18)
  - Milwaukee Dental Forum, Honorary Member, 1965 (Box 18)
  - J. C. Muhler Award, 1967; 1980 (Box 18)
  - Dr. Muhler's Curriculum Vitae, 1979-1987; undated (Box 18)
  - J. C. Muhler Publicity Folder, 1958-1969; undated (Box 18)
  - Multiple Principles of Preventative Dentistry Slide, undated (Box 18)
  - Naval Discharge, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Navy Presentation, 1967 (Box 18)
  - New York Academy of Sciences (Box 18)
  - N. Y. State Dental Journal, Charles F. Bodecker, Editor, 1957 (Box 18)
  - Nitrogen Fertilizer, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Nutrition Book Proposal, 1965 (Box 18)
  - Dr. O'Carroll, Topical Applications, 1961 (Box 18)
  - ORCA (Organization for Caries Research) Minutes, 1966; undated (Box 18)
  - Ottawa Dental Study Club, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1972-1978; 1989; undated (Box 18)
  - Ph. D. Requirements, 1950-1955; undated (Box 18)
  - Phi Delta Theta, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Phosphates and Dental Caries Conference, Houston TX, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Porta Pro Board of Directors, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Presentations and Papers by PDRI (Preventative Dentistry Research Institute) Staff, 1978; undated (Box 18)
  - Preventative Dentistry-General, 1962-1966; undated (Box 18)
  - Preventative Dentistry Lectures, 1952-1953; undated (Box 18)
  - PDRI Budget and Finances, 1970-1982 (Box 19)
  - Programs Available for Dental Societies, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Publicity, 1960-1962; 1980-1986; 1997; undated (Box 19)
  - Puerto Rico, 1967 (Box 19)
  - Reimbursement from IU Foundation through Dr. Hine, 1971-1980 (Box 19)
  - Reprints from ISDA (Indiana State Dental Association) Journal, 1958-1959; undated (Box 19)
  - The Review, Summer 1975 (Box 19)
  - San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1963-1965; undated (Box 19)
  - Science Lecture-Ball State University, February 1966 (Box 19)
  - Scientific Exhibit, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Sigma Xi, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Sisters of Providence, 1982-1987 (Box 19)
  - Dr. John R. Snyder, 1964; undated (Box 19)
  - Some Recent Advances in Nutrition, Spies, Tom, 1958 (Box 19)
  - Special Problems of Nutrition for Children, Rush, Byron K., 1963 (Box 19)
  - Speeches, Lectures, J. C. Muhler, 1975-1978 (Box 19)
  - Stannous Fluoride, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Students of Dr. Muhler, 1975-1979 (Box 19)
  - Student Theses (Box 19)
    - Abdul-Ghaffar, Hashim, 1959 (Box 19)
    - Barnes, George Parker, 1967 (Box 19)
    - Bean, F. E., 1968 (Box 19)
    - Brewer, Harold Eugene, 1958 (Box 19)
    - Brusch, Walter Albert, 1969 (Box 19)
    - Gish, Charles W., 1960 (Box 19)
    - Grutsch, James Francis, 1952 (Box 19)
    - Hutchins, Dale Wilton, 1967 (Box 19)
    - Hyde, Edward J., 1960 (Box 19)
    - Katz, Simon, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Kazlusky, Joseph B., 1969 (Box 19)
    - Lehman, David G., 1957 (Box 19)
    - Levy, Barbara Goldberg, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Student Theses (Box 20)
    - Light, James M., 1968 (Box 20)
    - McDonald Jr., James L., 1968 (Box 20)
    - Nazhat, Nehal Yahya, 1967 (Box 20)
    - O'Carroll, Francis M., 1962 (Box 20)
    - Oshiro, Raymond S., 1971 (Box 20)
    - Park, Ki ChuEl, 1969 (Box 20)
    - Price, Ely, 1956 (Box 20)
    - Stookey, George K., 1971 (Box 20)
    - Wagner, Martin James, 1958 (Box 20)
    - Weaver, Richard G., 1973 (Box 20)
    - Whitehurst, Virgil Edwards, 1968 (Box 20)
    - Williford, J., 1966 (Box 20)
  - Symposium, Applied Preventative Dentistry, 1965 (Box 20)
  - Toledo Dental Society Lecture, 1971 (Box 20)
  - University Club, 1977-1978 (Box 20)
  - U. S. Department of Health Education and Welfare (Food and Drug), 1972-1974; undated (Box 20)
  - U.S. Naval Dental School Lecture, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Washington Preventative Dentistry Course, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Water Fluoridation Projects, undated (Box 20)
  - Well House Society, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
  - Woodburn Guild, 1982 (Box 20)
- Correspondence, 1919-1996; undated (Box 21)
  - Advisory Committee, Institute for Advanced Study, Bloomington Campus, 1981 (Box 21)
  - American Dental Association, 1971-1976 (Box 21)
  - Army, Dr. Muhler's Consultant File, Fort Knox, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Beecham, Inc., 1970 (Box 21)
  - Brebeuf School, 1985-1992 (Box 21)
  - Brewer, Harold E., 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Bullard, Wade, 1983 (Box 21)
  - Campaigne, Dr. Earnest E., 1969 (Box 21)
  - Creative Kinetics, Inc., 1989 (Box 21)
  - C.V. Mosby Company (Box 21)
    - 1965-1971 (Box 21)
    - 1973-1979 (Box 21)
  - Dahl, Lillian, ref: papers, clinics, etc., 1953-1954 (Box 21)
  - Day, Harry (Box 21)
    - 1978-1985 (Box 21)
    - 1983-1995 (Box 21)
  - Deibel, Robert, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Engel, Ronald L., 1971 (Box 21)
  - FTC (Federal Trade Commission), 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Miss Fisk, 1952-1953 (Box 21)
  - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Henningsen, Fred, 1919; 1992; undated (Box 21)
  - Dean Hine, 1958-1965 (Box 21)
  - Dr. Hine, 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Hold Letters, 1966-1967 (Box 21)
  - Indiana State Board of Health, Dr. Mercer, 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - IU Foundation (Box 21)
    - 1952, 1980-1993; undated (Box 21)
    - 1972-1986 (Box 21)
  - Institute for Advanced Study (Box 21)
    - 1981-1983, undated (Box 21)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 21)
    - 1982-1986, undated (Box 21)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 21)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 21)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - IADR Meeting, San Francisco, 1968 (Box 21)
  - International Textbook Co., 1969 (Box 21)
  - Johnson Wax, Bills of Lading, Storage, 1978-1984 (Box 21)
  - Journal Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 21)
  - Journal of the American Medical Association, 1958-1963 (Box 21)
  - Journal of the American Pharmaceutical association, Mr. George B. Griffenhagen, editor, 1958-1959 (Box 21)
  - Juicy Letters, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Kebler, Carl J., Requests for Grants, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Kyes, Rear Admiral F. M., Navy, 1964-1969 (Box 21)
  - Letters to be Answered Dr. Muhler, 1974-1980; undated (Box 21)
  - Dean McDonald, 1971-1978; undated (Box 21)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1969 (Box 21)
  - Ostrom, Capt. C. A., Navy, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Peragom Press, New York, 1962-1963 (Box 21)
  - PDRI General Correspondence, 1974-1985 (Box 21)
  - PDRI Office Space Correspondence, 1974-1985 (Box 21)
  - Putt, Mark, 1983-1985; undated (Box 21)
  - Recruitment Letter, 1986-1987 (Box 21)
  - Replies on Nominations for Vice Pres. and Alumni of the Year Award, Dental Alumni, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Reprint Requests (Box 22)
    - 1954-1958 (Box 22)
    - 1973-1985 (Box 22)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 22)
  - Ryan, John W., 1979-1986 (Box 22)
  - St. Joseph County ASCS (Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service), 1969 (Box 22)
  - St. Joseph Hospital, 1987-1993 (Box 22)
  - St. Joseph Medical Center, 1989-1992 (Box 22)
  - Sisters of Providence, 1981-1986 (Box 22)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1985 (Box 22)
  - State Board of Health, 1956-1963; undated (Box 22)
  - W.B. Saunders Company, Bob Wright, 1958-1960 (Box 22)
  - Wells, Herman B, 1977-1996 (Box 22)
  - Wm. C. Brown Book Company, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
  - Yates, Eric, 1988-1990 (Box 22)
- Audio-Visual, undated (Box 23)
  - Lukas Productions 5285 Achieve and Fluoride A/B Versions -3 TV Spots, undated; 2 Reels 2 (Box 23)
    Negative and Optical Soundtrack -- for toothpaste called Achieve
  - Lukas Productions 5285 Achieve 60 - 100 People, undated; 4 Reels (Box 23)
    03- 2 commercials labeled "McCoy" and "Pastry Shop Lady" spliced together on 1 reel, for toothpaste called Fresh Look 04- Several commercials spliced together on 1 reel, for toothpaste called Fresh Look 05-/06- A/B rolls for Lucas Film - "Achieve"
  - Lukas Productions Fluoride 2:60, undated; 5 Reels (Box 23)
    06- A roll for Lucas commercial for toothpaste called "Achieve" 07- B roll for Lucas commercial for toothpaste called "Achieve" 08- C roll for Lucas commercial for toothpaste called "Achieve" 09- D roll for Lucas commercial for toothpaste called "Achieve" 10- E roll for Lucas commercial for toothpaste called "Achieve"
  - Master Mix w/ Check Prints, undated; 2 Reels (Box 23)
    Mag track and Print - for toothpaste called Achieve
  - RESTRICTED FILES (Box 27)